Hey, how's it going guys?
Welcome back to another advanced editor tutorial by Ads Rx.
This is part six, and we are gonna be going over video ad performance creatives.
This is a very, very important module. It contains a lot of information, uh,
whether you've been in this space, uh, a lot or for a long time or not,
I think this is very valuable. It'll provide you with a very, uh,
clear understanding or at least outlook on what's out there when it comes to
video ad creative and video performance creative. There's a lot to cover,
so let's just get straight into it. All right,
so the truth about video performance, I'm sorry.
The truth about performance ads is you're not here just to make things enjoyable
to watch. You're here to make things sell. Okay? There's a difference here. Uh,
when you're doing any type of marketing content, you know,
there has to be a result. It goes back to the direct response side of things.
And if you're putting stuff out there that isn't converting and it's not getting
attention and it's not getting clicks, then there's, you know, there's no point.
So in anything we do, we want to create some sort of,
we wanna establish some sort of connection here.
So this does require both creativity and critical thinking,
and that's why we call it performance ads, because you're not just, uh,
creating for the sake of creating, you're actually taking that,
applying the data,
and then leveraging creativity to create something special and
direct response. So that's where this Venn diagram comes from.
So on the left side, you see creativity, and that's your branding, copy,
design ideas, angles, content, look and feel. And on the right side,
you've got your data, which is your ad met metrics, your demographics,
income level keywords, targeting customer feedback, comments, seasonality,
all those other things that aren't creative related, right?
So in the middle where they meet is actually where performance creative lives.
So when you are a creative person, um,
typically we like to stay over here. Uh, it's just much more comfortable for us.
It's where we are able to, I would say,
be creative and we are more in flow state. Um,
but when we cross over to the data world, it starts to get a little boring.
I mean, I'm a creative guy, so getting into the data, it's not that it's boring,
it's just not as, uh, exciting. It's not as natural for us.
And same thing goes for, uh,
data-driven people or analytical people when they enter creative roles.
It's very, very challenging.
So that's why we need to combine the two in order to have the best
effect possible to produce the best results possible.
And that's where you get performance creative.
So four objectives to, uh, to add, sorry, lemme say that again.
Four objectives to performance ad creatives. Number one,
add breakdown analysis. Okay?
So you wanna make sure you're comparing data with the advertisement or the
advert. Number two, you wanna find the weaknesses of your ads.
Where can it be improved? Where can we speak things up? Where can we cut?
How can we make it more engaging? Number three,
iterating on winning angles. So how do we keep ads new and fresh?
'cause a certain, once you hit, uh, certain impressions or you,
your ads been viewed a certain amount of times,
it starts to decline in its performance. So how do you change that up?
Number four, develop new angles and styles. So how do you reach more people?
And this comes down to creating new pockets, uh, new angles,
testing different creators, testing different, um, people,
different scenarios. There's so much variety and it's never ending. Uh,
and a certain piece of content will resonate with a different audience.
So you don't wanna limit yourself.
You don't wanna say your X brand and you only work with X people and you're ex
this,
you're totally gonna exclude a lot of people who potentially could be interested
in your brand or your product. So we'll get into that in a little bit.